Node.js has been gathering a lot of attention lately.
最近 Node.js 吸引了很多人的眼球
Let's try to understand what Node.js is.
接下来让我们来看看 Node.js 到底是什么
And what role does NPM play, together,
以及 NPM 在和 Node.js 搭配使用时
with Node.js?
担当的是怎样的一个角色
Now what exactly is Node.js?
什么是 Node.js ?
Node.js is a JavaScript runtime that is built on
Node.js 是一个 JavaScript 运行环境
top of the Chrome V8 JavaScript Engine.
它基于 Chrome V8 JavaScript 引擎
The Chrome V8 JavaScript Engine was built originally to a part of
Chrome V8 JavaScript 引擎在一开始是
the Chrome browser and to support the JavaScript that runs within your browser.
Chrome 浏览器支持运行 JavaScript 的一个引擎
Now once you separate the engine out of the browser and
而现在 当你把这个引擎从浏览器里分离出来
let it run on your machine,
并让它在你的机器上运行时
you're able to support the running of JavaScript programs on your machine.
你的机器就能运行 JavaScript 程序了
Now this brings a lot of interesting capabilities.
这带来了许多有意思的功能
The node environment uses an event driven, non-blocking,
而 Node 环境则使用了事件驱动的 非阻塞的 IO 模型
I/O model which makes it very lightweight and
这使它能轻量级地 有效率地处理
efficient to handle primarily data driven websites.
主要是数据驱动的网站
We're gonna look at that aspect in a later course.
我们将在后续的课程中回过头来看这一些方面
Now, in this course we will look at nodes used primarily as a JavaScript runtime.
而现在 我们关心的主要是 Node 作为 JavaScript 运行环境时的表现
This is a quick overview of the node architecture.
这是一个 Node 的框架图
At the bottom layer of course, as they said node runs on top of
在底部有我们之前提到过
Google Chrome's V8 engine, so Chrome V8 engine it at the bottom together with
作为 Node 核心的 Google Chrome V8 引擎
libuv, which enables interaction with the underlying
位于同一层的还有 libuv 它允许你和更底层的计算机系统和设备
computer system, and the devices, and so on.
进行一些交互
And on top of that, we have node bindings, which are written in C++.
而在其上 也就是第二层 是完全用 C++ 写的 Node Bindings 库
The uppermost layer is the node core, or standard library,
至于第一层就是 Node 核心 或说标准库
we just completely implement it in JavaScript.
它是完全用 JavaScript 实现的
Now this is what we make use of.
而这一层也正是我们在使用 Node 运行环境时
When we use the node runtime.
要应用的一层
The node JavaScript runtime has been used in two different ways.
通常 Node 的 JavaScript 运行环境有两种用法
First, a lot of people have written a set of interesting web development utilities.
其一 很多人用 JavaScript 写了一系列 有趣的 web 开发工具
In JavaScript to run on node and support various use cases for web development.
这些工具能在 Node 上运行 并适用于多种多样的 web 开发用例
So we have tools like Bower, Grunt, Gulp, and so on,
比如著名的 Bower, Grunt, Gulp 等等
which are all written in JavaScript.
这些工具都是用 JavaScript 写的
We're gonna explore some of these in the next few lectures in this course.
我们将会在后续课程中着重探索其中的几个
Node also brings JavaScript to the server side.
其次 Node 同时也将 JavaScript 带到了服务端
Earlier when we looked at web development we saw that we needed to use
之前我在介绍 web 开发时曾提到过 传统上，开发服务器端时
a completely different language of the server side like ruby, python,
需另外使用 ruby, Python, Java ASP.Net, PHP 等等 (与 JS) 不同的后端开发语言
Java ASP.NET, PHP, and so on.
来实现服务端
With the availability of Node, you can start writing server-side
而有了 Node 之后 你就可以完全使用 JavaScript
implementation completely in JavaScript, so with a single language.
来实现服务端了
JavaScript in this case,
这样的话 你就可以只用 JavaScript 这一门语言
you are able to target both the front end as well as the back end.
来同时实现前端和后端
So that's the flexibility that node brings you for back end development.
这就是 Node 在后端开发上带给你的灵活性
We're gonna explore this part of it in a entirely different
我们会在这个专项课程中的另一门
course which will follow towards the later part of this specialization.
完全不同的课程中学习这部分内容
In the context of node you often
当你听到人们讨论 Node 的时候
hear people talk about the node package manager or NPM.
你会经常听到人们谈起 Node 的包管理器 简称 NPM
This is a manager that manages the ecosystem of node modules, or packages.
NPM 是 Node 模块 (以及包) 生态的管理器
A lot of people have already written
已经有很多人写了很多
very useful libraries that can be Used with node.
用于 Node 的实用类库
These are package in the form of node modules that you can download and
你可以下载这些模块形式的包到你的系统中
install within your system and make use of these libraries within your own
并在你自己的 Node 开发中
node development that you do in JavaScript.
灵活应用它们
We are gonna explore a little of this in this course but
我们会在这门课程中稍微学习一点这方面的知识
you will see a lot more of this in the server side node application use cases.
不过你将会更多的在服务端 Node 应用案例中 看到这方面的应用
Now, a node package contains the JavaScript files,
简单地说, Node 包是一些 JavaScript 文件的集合
which obviously implement the libraries, and
它们实现了一些库以及一个叫 package.json 的文件
also a file called package.json, which is like a manifest file.
这个文件如同包裹的内容说明
We're gonna look at an example of package.json for
我们将会在接下来的某几节课中
some use cases in some of the later lectures.
看到 package.json 的一些栗子并学习 如何设置并使用它
Now we'll move on to a couple of exercises where we learn more about node.
接下来我们将会进行一系列的练习 来熟悉 Node 的使用
We'll first look at setting up node and NPM.
我们将会先学习如何设置好 Node 和 NPM 然后我们将通过一些简单的例子
And then we'll understand node modules by implementing a very simple example.
来更好地理解 Node 模块 【翻译 - Carefree0910 校对 - Qiansen1386】